Guide to the Paul Langland Papers 1926-2011 MSS 253
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV: Posters, Programs and Flyers
  - Subseries A: Artists
    - Eric Bogosian, 1978; 1982; 1986 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Bread and Puppet Theater, 1974; undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - David Cale, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Channel Z, 1986; undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Ping Chong, 1982; 1984; 1988; 1992; undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Lucinda Childs, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Remy Charlip, 1980; 1984 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Merce Cunningham Dance Studio, 1977; 1982; 1984 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Tricia Brown, 1982; 1985; 1987-1989; 1990 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Contact Improvisation, 1975; 1978; 1984; 1988; 1990; 1997; undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Quentin Crisp, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Blanche Evan, 1964; 1974-1977; 1980-1982; undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Ellen Fisher, 1983-1984; 1984-1988; undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Simone Forti, 1979; 1988; 1995; 1998; undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Philip Glass, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Grand Union, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Spalding Gray, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Holly Hughes, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Bill Jones, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Paul Langland, 1968-1985 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Paul Langland, 1986-1995 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Paul Langland, 1996-2000 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Paul Langland, 2001-2006 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Paul Langland, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Paul Langland, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Daniel Lepkoff, 1979; 1987-1989; undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - The Living Theater, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Diane Madden, 1986; 1989; undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Nina Martin, 1984-1985; 1989-1990; undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Taylor Mead, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Tim Miller, 1984; undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Meredith Monk [1 of 2], 1974; 1979; 1981; 1983-2005 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Meredith Monk [2 of 2], 1974-2006; 2005; 2008 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Meredith Monk and Ping Chong [1 of 2], 1979-1986; undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Meredith Monk and Ping Chong [2 of 2], 1976; 1979 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Mark Morris, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Mary Overlie, 1977; 1981; 1987; 1998; undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Steve Paxton, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Steve Petronio, 1982; 1984; 1987-1988; undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Rediculous Theatrical Company, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Steve Reich, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Lily Tomlin, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Diane Torr, 1988; 1992; undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Peter Van Riper, circa 1979 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - David Zambrano, 1986-1988; 2000; undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Subseries B: Venues
    - BAM [Brooklyn Academy of Music], 1979; 1982-1984; 1986-1988; undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Dance Theater Workshop [1 of 2], 1982-1989; 1993-1998; undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Dance Theather Worshop [2 of 2], 1982-1989; 1993; 1998; undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Danspace, 1983-1988; 1990; 1996-1997; 1999; undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - La Mama [1 of 2], 1987-1989; 2001; 2008; undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - La Mama [2 of 2], 2001; 2008; undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Movement Research, 1978-1979; 1983; 1985; 1987-1988; 1993; 1998; 2003; 2004; 2008; 2011; undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - NYU Experimental Theater Wing/Tisch School of the Arts [1 of 2], 1982-1984; 1998; undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - NYU Experimental Theater Wing/Tisch School of the Arts [2 of 2], 1998; 2003-2011; undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - PS 122, 1981; 1983-1984; 1988-1989; 1990; undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Venues A-B, 1974; 1977-1978; 1981-1984; 1988; 1990; 1998-1999; 2001-2007; undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Venues C, 1978-1984; 1987-1989; 1993; 1999; 2005; 2009; undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Venues D-G, 1976-1989; 2002-2003; undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Venues H-J, 1979; 1986-1989; 1990; 1992; 2000-2003; undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Venues K-M, 1975; 1978-1988; 1995; 1999; 2004; 2008; undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Venues N-P, 1973; 1978; 1980-1989; 2001; 2005; 2011; 2012; undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Venues S-Z, 1976; 1982; 1988-1989; undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Venues, 1975; 1977; 1980; 1982; 1986-1989; 2002; undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified Venues, 1979-1980; 1984; 1987; 1988; undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Series V: Allan Wayne Material
  Series V contains both material belonging to Allan Wayne and material created by Paul Langland regarding his teaching of Allan Wayne's technique. The material belonging to Allan Wanye consists largely of dance programs featuring Wayne as a dancer. The material created by Paul Langland consists of notes and flyers regarding his classes on "Allan Wayne Work," as well as some biographical information on Allan Wayne
  Arrangement
  The arrangement of Series V reflects Paul Langland's original arrangement of the material.
  - Allan Wayne Material, 1926-1932; 1941; 2000; 2001; 2004; undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Allan Wayne Material, 1998; 2000; 2002; 2004; undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    The material in this folder seems to correspond to Tapes 1-12 in Series Vi: Video.
  - [Allan Wayne Dance Programs], 1926-1943 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - [Allan Wayne Photo Album] (Binder 18)
- Series VI: Video
  Series VI consists largely of video recordings of Paul Langland's performances. It includes recordings of both Paul Langland's choreography as well as his performances with the Meredith Monk Company, and other dance collaborations. It includes final recordings as well as some unedited material.
  Series VI also includes three films.
  Series VI is arranged chronologically. Undated material is arranged alphabetically following the dated material.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Only materials listed under Series A; Access Copies are available to researchers. Access copies may not be available for all video material. Please consult a Fales Archivist.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    - Fame and Money, 5/11/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0390)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Format: DVD
      TRT: 00:08:30
      Original Format: VHS
    - Fame and Money, DTW, 11/25/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0387)
      TRT: 00:03:55
    - Emotional Corridors, Channel Z Master, 1/1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0510)
      TRT: 00:07:59
    - Channel Z Number 1, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 28, 1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0516)
      TRT: 00:47:04
    - Channel Z Number 2, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 28, 1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0495)
      TRT: 00:47:55
    - Channel Z Number Three, Ethnic Folk Arts, 1/28/84, 1/28/1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0492)
      TRT: 00:51:29
    - Channel Z Number 4, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, 1/30/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0489)
      TRT: 01:05:54
    - Channel Z Number Six, Ethnic Folk Arts, 1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0486)
      TRT: 00:53:05
    - Circa 1950-1951, DTW, 11/1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0360)
      TRT:00:30:37
    - "Eddie" Benefit for the Homeless, 984, 1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0384)
      TRT: 00:12:13
    - Laff at the Fags, by Scott Heron and Eric Paulo, 1985 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0381)
      TRT: 00:32:32
    - Tom Lyman, 1/31/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0378)
      TRT: 00:42:31
    - Combing the Will, 12/1987 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0375)
      TRT: 00:19:07
    - Aquarium, Michelle, Left Eye, Right Monitor. 4/28/88 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0372)
      Original Format: DVD
      TRT: 00:32:44
    - Aquarium, Elisa, Right Eye, Left Monitor, 4/28/88 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0369)
      TRT: 00:07:22
    - Emotional Corridors TNG, 4/28/88 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0366)
      TRT: 00:14:16
    - Emotional Corridors, TNG, NYU ETW, 5/5/88 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0363)
      TRT: 01:07:45
    - Section 6 Movement Track Performance, NYU ETW, 5/5/88 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0357)
      TRT: 01:53:00
    - Kitchen Concert, 12/1988 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0354)
      TRT: 00:28:15
    - Langland Excerpts 1988 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0393)
      TRT: 00:36:00
    - Paul Solos, Movement Track Improvs., 1988 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0345)
      TRT: 00:59:41
    - Pool Pictures, Aug. 27, 1989 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0348)
      TRT: 00:48:39
    - Jungle Breath, Hillsdale, Oct.21,1989 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0351)
      TRT: 01:10:13
    - Waterfall, 1989 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0339)
      TRT: 00:08:21
    - Section 4 Footage, Work Tape ETW. 1989 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0336)
      TRT: 01:22:36
    - Paul and Gail Worktape, MM College, Jan. 1990 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0333)
      TRT: 02:02:00
    - Rudie to Paul, Project Diary (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0330)
      TRT: 00:44:58
    - [1]-- Waterfall [2]-- Jonah, Performance Edit, 4/27/90 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0327)
      TRT: 00:15:30
    - The Ghost of a Flea, 5/26/90, 5/26/1990 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 258.0525)
      TRT: 00:52:00
      Original Format: Video Cassette
    - Spectra, Hilldale, NY, 8/18/90, 8/18/1990 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0321)
      TRT: 00:53:00
    - Arts Panorama, 8/23/90, 8/23/1990 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0318)
      TRT: 00:44:51
    - Untitled, Aug. 1990 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0324)
    - Paul, Theatre Thala, Gothenbur, Sweden, 10/26/1990 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0315)
      TRT: 00:34:00
    - Location of Lone Dance Collection, 12/19/19[90] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0312)
      TRT: 00:16:00
    - Normal Kansas, ETW Mainstage II, Copy of Super 8, April 1991 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0309)
      TRT: 01:26:00
    - Downtown Upstate, Wide Angle, 10/25/91, 10/25/1991 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0426)
      TRT: 01:23:50
    - We Interrupt This Program... Day Without Art, 1991 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0432)
      TRT: 01:03:00
    - A Voice for All, NYU ETW AIDS Week, 1991, Tape 1 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0429)
      TRT: 02:00:00
    - A Voice for All, NYU ETW AIDS Week, 1991, Tape 2 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0435)
      TRT: 00:54:00
    - Downtown Upstate, 1991 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0417)
      TRT: 00:27:00
    - Paul Langland ETW Class, 1992 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0420)
      TRT: 00:24:00
    - [1]-- Angels and Apes Trio, NYC, 4/93 [2]-- Saint Marks church Trio, 12/93, [1]-- 4/1993 [2]-- 12/1993 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0423)
      TRT: 00:44:31
    - Full Flora Smak, NYU, 1994 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0408)
      TRT: 01:07:40
    - Almost Rapture Rehersal, 11/28/95, 11/28/1995 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0411)
      TRT: 00:12:10
    - Dybbuks and Chicken Soup, 1995 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0414)
    - Untitled Duet, Paul Langland and Brendan McCall, DanceFest5, 1995 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0438)
      TRT: 00:03:00
    - Section Seven Class Showing Choreography, 3/98, 3/1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0402)
      TRT: 00:25:30
    - [1]- Almost Rapture, Solo [2]-- Honnor, Excerpt. Dixon Place, 4/28/98, 4/28/1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0405)
      TRT: 00:12:40
    - Honor, Tisch NYU-Danspace Project Master, 5/17/1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0528)
      TRT: 00:46:00
    - Tape 1, AW Warm Up, Cellular Introduation, Cellular Discussion, [1998] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0531)
      TRT: 01:40:00
    - Tape 2, [AW Warm Up, Cellular Introduction, Cellular Discussion, 1998] (Shelf Media, Media Id: 253.0534)
      TRT: 001:30:00
    - Tape 4, 11/18/88, 11/18/1998 (Shelf Media, Media Id: 253.0537)
      TRT: 01:49:00
    - Tape 5, Four Fluid Reviews and Comp.Review, Cellular, Lymph, Int. Cell, Fascia, 11/20/98, 11/20/1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0540)
      TRT: 01:19:18
    - Tap 6, AW Wall Work and Dancing [1998] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0543)
    - Tape 7, CSK Duets and Solos 11/30/98, 11/30/1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0546)
      TRT: 01:51:00
    - Tape 8, CSK AW including Scalpel, December 3, 1998, 12/3/1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0549)
    - Tape 9, Venus Group Impo [12/2] 1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0552)
      TRT: 01:47:00
    - Tape 10, Synovial, Venus Duet Phrases [12/4] 1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0555)
      TRT: 01:48:00
    - Tape 11, Alex on the Floor, AW Standing Barr Arterial [12/7]1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0558)
      TRT: 01:37:00
    - Tape 12, Fluids Project, Self Directed [Warm Up] 12/9/98, 12/9/1998 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0561)
      TRT: 01:15:00
    - Spontaneous Combustion Cabaret, Northampton, MA (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0399)
      TRT: 01:16:35
    - 7th World AIDS Day, 9th NY Improv Fest. DansSpace Project, 12/1/00, 12/1/2000 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0396)
      TRT: 00:21:57
    - [1]-- Animas [2]-- Heat, UC Davis, 4/14/01, 4/14/2001 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0468)
      TRT: 00:45:00
    - Getting Ready to Leave, Amherst Colle, 6/2001 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0471)
      TRT: 00:15:00
    - Scratch, IFNY 310, Danspace Project, 11/29/01, 11/29/2001 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0477)
      TRT: 00:23:00
    - My Improv Festival Scratch, 12/2001 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0480)
    - Four Solos, Jewel Theatre, Luther College, 1/9/04, 1/9/2004 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0474)
      TRT: 01:08:15
    - TSL, Four Solos Master, 7/10/04, 7/10/2004 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0564)
      TRT: 00:50:00
    - Z Boys; October 1984 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0194)
      TRT: 00:07:42
      Original Format: 3/4" Umatic
    - 20 Minute Black, Class Acts Title (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0459)
      TRT: 00:11:10
    - Paul Langland and David Lepkoff- Alabama (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0483)
      TRT: 01:08:00
    - Allan Wayne Tape (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0465)
      TRT: 01:11:00
    - Almost Rapture and Other Dance Surprises, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0182)
      TRT: 00:48:00
    - [1]-- Coffee [2]-- Trio: Angels and Apes [3]-- Trio: St Mark's Church, 1993 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0185)
      TRT: 00:50:47
    - Boomerang (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0456)
      TRT: 00:14:46
    - Brendan and Paul Fuck Around (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0453)
      TRT: 00:26:00
    - Domestic Virtue Master (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0462)
      TRT: 01:23:00
      Original Format: Video8
    - Domestic Virtue-- Master (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0498)
      TRT: 01:47:45
    - E.T.W. Festival Day (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0446)
      TRT: 01:56:39
    - Dolmen Music; April 2004 / Meredith Monk (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0188)
      TRT: 00:25:00
    - The Ghost of a Flea, PS 122, Tight Angle (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0444)
      TRT: 00:47:19
    - The Ghost of a Flea, PS 122, Wide Angle (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0441)
      TRT: 00:46:34
    - Honda Commercials Auditions (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0450)
      Related Archival Materials note
      TRT: 00:25:46
    - Kinetic Fairy Tale, Master (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0504)
      TRT: 00:07:03
    - [1]-- Lumberjack Jig [2]-- Raw Footage (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0519)
      TRT: 00:30:10
    - [1]-- Man and Machine [2]-- Waterfall [3]-- Jonah, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0179)
      TRT: 00:20:00
    - Movement Track, Third Night, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0342)
    - [Normal Kansas], Act 1 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0522)
      TRT: 00:50:16
    - Normal Kansas, Act 2 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0507)
      TRT: 00:11:33
    - Normal Kansas, Act 3 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0513)
      TRT: 00:36:19
    - A Woodcutters Dream (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0501)
      TRT: 00:03:59
    - Whopee in the Dark; October 2002 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0191)
      TRT: 01:07:00
    - Z Boys, 1984/2004 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0195)
      Format: VHS
      TRT: 00:08:00
    - Heat, University of California Davis, 2001 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 253.0196)
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Quarry: An opera my Meredith Monk performance at BAM, January 10, 1977 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0010)
      TRT: unknown
    - The Travelogue Series, Roudabout Theatre, New York City, March 1977 - Tape 1 of 3 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0012)
    - The Travelogue Series, Roundabout Theatre, New York City, March 1977 - Tape 2 of 3 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0013)
    - The Travelogue Series, Roundabout Theatre, New York City, March 1977 - Tape 3 of 3 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0014)
    - Recent Ruins at LaMama, November 1979 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0015)
    - Recent Ruins at LaMama, November 1979 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0016)
      Format: Video 8mm
    - Meredith Monk Vocal Ensemble, Dolmen Music at Washington Hall Performance Gallery, January 17, 1982 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0017)
    - Meredith Monk Vocal Ensemble, Dolmen Music at Washington Hall Performance Gallery, January 17, 1982 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0018)
    - Speciman Days at The Public Theater, February 24, 1982 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0197)
    - Turtle Dreams (Waltz), 1983 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0019)
      TRT: 00:29:00
    - Fame and Money, Choreography Fellowship Application Support Tape, May 11, 1984 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0020)
      TRT: 00:8:30
    - Emotional Corridors, Channel Z Master, [January 1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0198)
    - Channel Z Number 1, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 28, 1984 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0199)
    - Channel Z Number 2, Ethnic Folk Arts Center, January 28, 1984 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0200)
    - Channel Z Number Three, Ethnic Folk Arts, January 28, 1984, January 29, 1984 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0201)
    - Channel Z Number 4, Ethnic Folk Arts, January 30, 1984 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0202)
    - Channel Z Number 5, Ethnic Performance Rehersal, [1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0203)
    - Channel Z Number 6, Ethnic Folk Arts, January 30, [1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0204)
    - Z Boys, Jeff Turtletaub Edit, October 19, 1984 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0205)
    - Fame and Money, DTW, November 25, 1984 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0021)
    - Circa 1950-1951, DTW, November 1984 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0032)
    - "Eddie" Benefit for the Homeless, 1984 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0022)
    - Randy Warshaw, Sunday Nite, January 20, 1985 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0206)
    - Excerpts, May 1985 [1] -- Boomerang [2] -- Rapture [3] -- Domestic Virtue or Bingo Rocks the House [4] -- Jungle Breath (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0044)
      Participants: Jungle Breath - Daniel Lepkoff, Domestic Virtue, Barbara Hofrenning
    - Molly, November 26, 1985 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0208)
      Format: 3/4 un. Umatic
    - Laff at the Fags, by Scott Heron and Eric Paulo, 1985 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0023)
    - [1] -- Rapture [2] -- Candle Dance [3] -- Fame and Money. Munich and Erlangen, Germany, March 1986 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0024)
    - [1] -- Rapture [2] -- Candle Solo. Munich, April 1986 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0025)
    - [1] -- Raputre [2] -- The Candle Solo. Munich and Erlangen, Germany, April 1986 (Box 38, Media ID: 253.0154)
    - Channel Z [1]-- Pepsico Festival, 1986 [2]-- Z Boys Video [3]-- PS122, February 1986 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0207)
    - Tom Lyman, January 31, 1987 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0026)
    - Dances in the Environs, Global Village Artist-in-Residence Grants Application [1]-- Mand and Machine [2]-- Kinetic Fairy Tale, September 1, 1987 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0209)
    - Combing the Will, December 1987 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0027)
      General Note
      Participants: Barbara Hofrenning
    - Aquarium. Michelle, Left Eye, Right Monitor, April 28, 1988 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0028)
    - Aquarium. Elisa, Right Eye, Left Monitor, April 28, 1988 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0029)
    - Emotional Corridors TNG, April 28, 1988 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0030)
    - Emotional Corridors, The Next Generation. New York University Experimental Theatre Wing Movement Track, May 5, 1988 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0031)
    - Section 6 Movement Track Performance, NYU ETW, May 5, 1988 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0033)
    - Kitchen Concert, December 1988 (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0034)
      Credit: Mary Overlie
    - Paul Langland Excerpts, 1988 [1] -- Jungle Breath [2] -- Man and Machine [3] -- Eddie [4] -- Fame and Money (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0035)
      Participants: Jungle Breath - Daniel Lepkoff
    - Paul Langland Excerpts, 1988 [1] -- Jungle Breath [2] -- Man and Machine [3] -- Eddie [4] -- Fame and Money (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0036)
    - Paul Langland Excerpts, 1988 [1] -- Jungle Breath [2] -- Man and Machine [3] -- Eddie [4] -- Fame and Money (Box 34, Media ID: 253.0037)
    - Jungle Breath, 1988 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0211)
    - Paul Solos, Movement Track Improvs., 1988 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0039)
    - 2 Works, Compiled January 1989 [1] -- Jungle Breath [2] -- Domestic Virtue (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0040)
    - 2 Works, Compiled January 1989 [1] -- Jungle Breath [2] -- Domestic Virtue (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0041)
    - Hofrenning/Langland, February 1, 1989 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0042)
      TRT: 00:9:30
    - Excerpts, April 1989 [1] -- Boomerang [2] -- Domestic Virtue, or Bingo Rocks the House (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0043)
      Participants: Domestic Virtue, Barbara Hofrenning
    - Pool Pictures, August 27, 1989, August 1989 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0045)
    - Jungle Breath, Hillsdale, October 21, 1989 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0046)
    - Paul Langland American Choreographer Awards Application [1] -- Boomerang [2] -- Rapture [3] -- Domestic Virtue [4] -- Jungle Breath, 1989 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0047)
    - Excerpts, New York Foundation Choreography Application, 1989 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0048)
    - Waterfall, 1989 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0049)
    - Section 4 Footage, Work Tape, ETW, 1989 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0050)
    - Original Unedited Footage and Edited Pieces, 1989-90, 1989, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0051)
    - Paul and Gail Worktape, MM Collage, January 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0052)
    - Rudie to Paul, Project Diary, February 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0053)
    - Art Matters Grant Application, Three Pieces [1]-- Waterfall [2]-- I Feel I Am [3]-- Jungle Breath, February 1990 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0210)
    - [1] -- Man and Machine [2] -- Waterfall, February 14, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0054)
      Format: Betamax
    - [1]-- Waterfall [2]-- Jonah, Performance Edit, 4/27/90, April 27, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0058)
    - The Ghost of a Flea, Hadley Copy, May 6, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0059)
    - Excerpts from the Ghost of a Flea, Recorded May 25, 1990 for Choreograpger Fellowship Application (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0060)
    - The Ghost of a Flea, Recorded May 26, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0061)
    - The Ghost of a Flea, May 26, 1990 (Box 39, Media ID: 253.0212)
      Format: 3/4 in. Umatic
    - The Ghost of a Flea, May 26, 1990, NYFA Application (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0213)
    - The Ghost of a Flea at P.S. 122, May 26, 1990 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0214)
    - Diary, Venezuela. Danny, Paul, July 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0057)
    - Spectra, Hillsdale, NY, August 18, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0063)
    - Arts Panorama, August 23, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0064)
    - Untitled, August 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0062)
    - Paul, Theatre Thala, Gothenbur, Sweeden, October 26, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0065)
    - Location of Lone Dance Collection, December 19, 19[90] (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0065)
    - Jungle Breath, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0056)
      TRT: 00:18:00
    - Jonah, 1990 (Box 40, Media ID: 253.0215)
    - Excerpt, The Ghost of a Flea, Paul Langland New Forms Application, 1990 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0067)
    - Normal Kansas, ETW Mainstage II, Copy of Super 8, April 1991 (Box 35, Media ID: 253.0068)
    - Downtown Upstate, Wide Angle, October 25, 1991 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0069)
    - We Interrupt This Program...Day Without Art, Live Television Broadcast, 1991 (Box 36, Media ID: 253.0070)